Guide to the Linlithgow and Stirlingshire Hunt Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Linlithgow and Stirlingshire Hunt records
1825-1954
1877-1940
GEN MSS 884
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
1.67
(4 boxes)
The records consist of secretaries' minutes, correspondence, subscriber lists, narrative reports of hunts, and records for Hunt-sponsored events such as the annual judging of the young hounds and the Hunt Ball, steeplechases, and Gamekeepers' and Earthstoppers' lunches and shoots. The material primarily dates from 1877, when the Linlithgow and Stirlingshire Hunt was reorganized, but also contains some records from the Lothians' Hunt period. The material was used by Hunt secretary James H. Rutherfurd for his 1911 volume The History of the Linlithgow and Stirlingshire Hunt, 1775-1910.
Linlithgow and Stirlingshire Hunt
Lothians' Hunt
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Julian Browning on the Jonathan O. Bulkley Fund, 1998.
Linlithgow and Stirlingshire Hunt
The Linlithgow and Stirlingshire Hunt, Scotland's oldest country hunt, was organized in 1775. Between 1869 and 1877 it merged with the Lothians' Hunt and operated under the latter name; after 1877 it was revived as the Linlithgow and Stirlingshire Hunt.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: I. Administrative Records, 1825-1948. II. Correspondence, 1872-1940. III. Events Records, 1885-1954.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of secretaries' minutes, correspondence, subscriber lists, narrative reports of hunts, and records for Hunt-sponsored events such as the annual judging of the young hounds and the Hunt Ball, steeplechases, and Gamekeepers' and Earthstoppers' lunches and shoots. The material primarily dates from 1877, when the Linlithgow and Stirlingshire Hunt was reorganized, but also contains some records from the Lothians' Hunt period. The material was used by Hunt secretary James H. Rutherfurd for his 1911 volume The History of the Linlithgow and Stirlingshire Hunt, 1775-1910.
Fox hunting -- Scotland; Hunters -- Scotland; Hunting -- Scotland; Linlithgowshire (Scotland); Lothian (Scotland); Stirlingshire (Scotland); Minute books -- Scotland -- 19th century; Minute books -- Scotland -- 20th Century; Hunters -- Scotland -- 19th century; Rutherfurd, James H.; Rutherfurd, James H. ( History of the Linlithgow and Stirlingshire Hunt, 1775-1910); Lothians' Hunt; Linlithgow and Stirlingshire Hunt
- Administrative Records, 1825-1948; Series I; 12
  - Minutes of meetings, 1825, 1869-1887 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    With list of subscribers of 1825 tipped in the index pages between V and W. Also contains hunt reports clipped from newspapers and other ephemera documenting hunt activities
  - Minutes of meetings, 1923, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Blank ledger book, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letters of financial guarantee, 1912-1915 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - List of subscribers and expenses for 1810-1814, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Lists of subscribers, 1877-1887 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Lists of subscribers, 1921-1932 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Lists of those to whom cub-hunting cards are sent (subscribers), 1934-1937 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Copies of newspaper reports and cuttings from The Scotsman for season 1933-1934 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Report and Accounts for Season 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Four copies of a published report
  - Stamp book (postage accounts), 1924-1931 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1915-1945 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1872-1940; Series II; 7
  - Letterbook, 1872-1875 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - General correspondence, 1910-1924 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Letterpress copybook, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - General correspondence, 1931-1940 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Letters regarding the kennels and hounds, 1903-1938 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Letters regarding Golfhall Kennels and the Edinburgh-Glasgow Road widening project, 1924-1929 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Unused letterhead, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Events Records, 1885-1954; Series III; 20
  - Gamekeepers' and Earthstoppers' subscriptions and Lunch and Shoot records, 1885-1939 (Box 3, Folder 20-27)
  - Hunt Ball, 1926-1954 (Box 4, Folder 28-31)
  - Hunt date cards (recording dates of hunts), 1927-1940 (Box 4, Folder 32-33)
  - Young Hounds judging and luncheon (Puppy Show), 1927-1941 (Box 4, Folder 34-39)